I expected this,
but I'm amazed at this attack's
lack of planning.
Emergency requisitioning of jackets
and gloves to keep out the cold!
Did the Lieutenant General not know
that it gets cold on top of mountains, Suya?
It pains me to know that my allies on
the front lines are suffering in the cold.
You're as kind as
the holy mother herself, Suya!
When you're feeling cold,
I'll hold you tight to warm you up, okay?
Just start a fire.
Anyway, we're almost there.
One, two, three, four...
Huh? There's not enough.
Again, huh?
Check's complete.
I see.
Bye.
Oh, excuse me.
The officer cadets
are to go to that tent.
The commander wishes to see you.
There were 124 casualties
in yesterday's battle.
Northern Garrison Command Room
Among them—
What's taking so damn long?!
It's been three weeks!
The men are unused to high elevations
and have encountered several
unexpected obstacles.
We should withdraw—
We're fighting a bunch of mountain monkeys!
The only choice is to advance!
Withdraw our troops?
What are you thinking?
We spread the bait.
That's all.
First Lieutenant Amuse Sulkatta
Your next orders are to transport supplies
to the next supply point.
You'll be taking the same things as before.
Any questions?
Does that mean we're being sent
to the front lines as well?
I wouldn't say the front line, exactly...
It's just closer to the combat zone
than you are now.
Any other questions?
First Lieutenant,
I don't see any medics here.
Where are they?
They left for where you're going now.
There's a dire need for a field hospital.
First we're taken off the reserves,
and now we're heading to
the front lines, huh?
If Haro and the others are there already...
Yeah.
Things must be really hot at the front lines.
Alafatra Mountains
3600 meters above sea level
Push... push...
I'm tougher than I thought.
Come on, Azan. Focus on your breathing.
If you pant, it will only tire you more.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm sorry, Private First Class Kanna.
Halt!
Stronghold to our front!
Scouts!
It's abandoned. Perfect.
And it's on high ground, too.
Okay, all units will remain here.
This can be our camp.
Now we won't have to climb
any more for a while.
You are to defend this location to
the death until further orders!
Yes, sir!
Haro!
It's been a while.
Want to eat together?
Doesn't this ruin your appetite?
It's perfect. I don't have any
tomatoes to go with the meal.
Looks like the field hospital's
busy every day, huh?
Yes.
We're almost out of bandages and medicine.
For our part, we kept
running transport missions
until we ended up out here.
This isn't the rear anymore, is it?
Ikta-san,
I want to go make a proposal to headquarters.
Yeah, you should.
The field hospital should be
further to the rear,
or more specifically, someplace lower.
Ikta-san, when did you...
I've seen a lot of soldiers being
carried down the mountain
with no external wounds.
So you noticed...
Enemy attack!
Someone fight them!
Ikta Platoon, Matthew Platoon,
Torway Platoon,
grab your weapons and line up near the tents!
The Yatorishino Cavalry Platoon
is to mount and stand by here.
The enemy...
Where's the enemy?
They've launched a night attack, Captain.
The enemy probably isn't using any light.
Captain Hilmish Nikafarma
I-I see.
If we just let the defending
force handle it...
Our platoons will stand by with our weapons
to the rear of the defending force, then.
If the tide turns against us,
we'll offer support.
Yes.
That's right!
Hey, Ikta.
Shouldn't we meet up
with the defending force?
There's a lot of chaos at the front.
If we rush there, we'll be caught up in it.
And the captain there will be in control.
Meaning you're our temporary leader, Ikta?
You want to attack if possible, right?
And I want to move as little as possible,
so our interests coincide.
Oh, could you see it on my face?
I'll have to learn to control myself better.
The enemy?
No, allies.
They're being chased from the rear.
This isn't good.
They're out of formation.
Both enemy and ally are following after them.
All infantry, ready your swords!
Warrant Officers Torway and Matthew,
do not open fire until
our allies have passed!
Ikta Platoon's light troops,
prepare to attack!
Equip your partner to your crossbows!
Yatorishino's Cavalry Platoon
is to stand by to the rear.
I'll send the attack signal later!
Ikta, I know it's embarrassing,
but can I ask you something?
Anything, my friend Matthew.
How can I be as calm as you?
Once upon a time there was a brave general,
and a cowardly general.
One day the cowardly general
asked the brave general,
"How can I avoid being afraid of battle?"
The brave general asked him
a question instead.
"How can I stay sane in
that hell, like you do?"
You've recognized your cowardice,
and you want to fix it.
Which means you're more
than calm enough already.
Matthew!
Ikta Platoon, aim forward!
Beams on!
Charge!
A second wave's coming!
Matthew! Torway!
Fire!
Okay, finish it!
Yatori!
Charge!
All troops, draw swords!
Charge through the middle to split the enemy,
and then wipe them out!
Don't separate!
Regroup!
Warrant Officer, the enemy was
almost completely eliminated.
No casualties on our side.
It was...
Too easy?
No... Um...
If you thought it was easy, good.
If it's a bad job, you should
at least make it easy.
Are you okay?
I'm really sorry, um...
What?
Thanks for all this...
You kind of remind me of my mom.
Give me a break.
I'm not that old—
Well, I was married.
You were?
He died right after,
and his family kicked me out.
The only thing they gave me was a book.
A book?
They had this huge library.
When I wasn't doing chores, I'd always read.
You really do like books.
Yeah, they're great.
It's like your whole world's expanding.
Especially the Great Alafatra Survey Records.
Come to think of it, I wonder
if Ikkun-dono is doing well.
Ikkun-dono?
He's a weird guy,
but he'd read that book,
and he said I was a fellow student.
Are you close?
No, we just met each other twice.
He's like a book, though—he knows a lot.
You're looking forward to
seeing him again, then?
Yeah.
What should I ask him the next time we meet?
We're completely surrounded.
They deliberately left the fortress empty.
We've fallen into a trap!
Hey, Suya,
our mission was to deliver supplies
to the camp at the front lines, right?
Yes.
If necessary, I can repeat it to you.
The camp was taken?!
Curse you!
First Lieutenant Manubans Najiru
Now we can't deliver the supplies!
That's their goal, probably.
We'll need a full reevaluation
of our supply lines.
You're overstepping your bounds!
Warrant Officer Ikta!
Warrant Officer Matthew!
I order your group to perform
force reconnaissance!
Um... First Lieutenant Najiru?
The enemy has approximately
two platoons worth of soldiers.
It may be a bad idea to fight them in equal
numbers under unfavorable conditions.
Shut up!
The order's been given!
Can you at least give us
Torway's platoon as support, then?
Shut up!
I'll go! Please let me go, First Lieutenant!
Silence!
One hour.
How about that?
What?
I'll take the whole thing back in an hour...
if you leave it to my platoon.
That's crazy.
You can't bring down
that fortress in an hour.
Matthew, my friend,
if this goes well, it won't take 20 minutes.
Right, hottie?
If we are thinking the same thing,
it won't take that much time.
As long as we can get in position...
I'll give you six from my platoon,
including me.
Wait, what's the plan here?
You have Torway provide
fire support from above,
and we charge in?
That's right.
Worried about something, Matthew?
I'm worried about everything!
An air gun has an effective range
of 40 meters at best!
There's 150 meters from there
to the enemy camp!
It's not going to hit!
And with only six people,
you can't fire enough bullets
to make up for the drop in accuracy.
Thank you for that excellent summary.
You're very good at making it easy
for others to understand
what it is that you don't understand.
That's not a compliment!
And it's because nothing you do
ever makes any sense!
Now, now, calm down.
You'll know soon.
The enemy's here!
Everyone get to your positions!
Get that cannon ready!
Don't rush. Let them get closer.
Ready, now!
Where are they firing from?
The trick is to aim at
the artillery soldier's chest.
Equip the bullet.
Aim at the man to the left.
How can he hit them from so far away?
He dug small ridges in the barrel
of the gun to make the bullet spin.
That makes it go in a straighter line,
and a more stable trajectory.
That alone makes it around five times
more accurate than a normal air gun.
It's new technology that old man Anarai
put into use in Kioka,
and told me about, too.
The air rifle.
No enemies in sight.
Consider them suppressed.
Proceeding to support Point Two.
It's about time, huh?
Okay, charge!
The bullet's path is amazingly stable.
It's much less open to luck.
This really is revolutionary.
So this is part of the technology
hidden in Anarai's box?
It's still a prototype,
so there are only 40 of them.
The Empire lost a valuable man to Kioka.
Or perhaps I should say a terrifying man.
Don't worry about that.
Old man Anarai wouldn't want one country
to have a technological advantage.
He's very concerned with
keeping things balanced.
I still can't believe you shut down
six cannons with three shooters.
I think these air rifles are going to
change what it means to be a gunner.
And to adapt to this new era of technology,
I came up with a new class
of soldier, called a "sniper."
"Sniper?"
Warrant Officer Solork!
I'm coming to you since
First Lieutenant Najiru is absent!
The camp on the front lines
is requesting aid!
32nd Air Gun Platoon Sergeant Major Higgins
My camp, a day away by foot,
is surrounded by the enemy
and in danger of being wiped out!
You must go to rescue them immediately!
Hey, are you okay?
Call a medic.
And tell no one of this.
I'll give the orders.
None of the superior officers have realized.
Halt!
We will make camp for two days here!
Ikkun, there's no time to rest!
What do you mean?
We don't know what's going on over there!
Our troops still have the strength to go on!
That's not the problem.
There's another reason we have
to wait two days here to prepare,
or we can't go any higher up.
We need to adapt to the altitude.
We're fighting a deadly battle on
top of the Great Alafatra Mountains.
If you want to do something weird like that,
you need to obey the rules of high places.
The rules of high places?
The air is thinner up high.
That causes all kinds of sickness.
Dr. Anarai called it Alpine Sickness.
Hey, hang in there!
He's so frail...
Help me, Azan.
Azan?
It's dark...
It's so dark, even though it's midday.
Azan!
My highest priority is
keeping my comrades here safe.
And in order to do that,
I cannot skip the altitude adaptation step.
So we can't go save them yet.
Not until two days pass and
your bodies adapt to this altitude.
This is an order.
Please follow it.
Halt!
Well?
How's it look, Ikta?
I'm willing to attack immediately.
No need.
I don't see any allies
moving in the fortress.
Which means it's all over.
We had the choice to go save them, or not.
The risks, the chances of victory...
I hate to say it,
but sometimes on the battlefield
you have to make hard choices.
We won't be able to carry the bodies down—
Get the tags from the dead commander...
Ikta?
Of all the places...
I met you twice.
You're a weird guy, Ikkun.
I...
I was looking forward to the third time.
Goodbye, Kanna.
A splendid victory,
brought about by his command,
and a bitter conclusion,
brought about by his choice.
Ikta Solork gained both on this battlefield.
Someday, For The Third Time
Next time: "The Fate of a Small Reputation."
The Fate of a Small Reputation